STEPHEN K. HAGE

Stephen.Hage@gmail.com ► Linkedin.com/in/StephenHage ► stephenhage.github.io/ ► public.tableau.com/profile/stephen.hage/

SUMMARY

Data professional with six years of advanced analytics and data science experience, six years of sales and marketing work, and a MS in Predictive Analytics to be conferred in early 2019. Skilled in machine learning and deep learning techniques, uniquely combined with business decision-making and strategic thinking.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rakuten Marketing, Senior Analyst

May 2014-Present

Rakuten Marketing is the leader in ecommerce marketing services including SEM, Display, and Affiliate Marketing

- Increased new customer acquisition rate by 29% for a top client by developing complete end-to-end Conquesting Strategy, from data mining through the presentation to the client's marketing executives
- Improved Return on Ad Spend by 26% for a top-5 client by modeling elasticity of demand for advertising rates
- Enhanced competitive intelligence for sales and client services by developing web scrapers in Python
- Initiated, designed and deployed an automated mass forecasting tool to predict revenues by client by day

Rakuten Marketing, Account Manager

March 2012-May 2014

- Built Excel templates to standardize decision-making for ad buying decisions for client services
- Wrote series of explainer documents for Account Managers to demonstrate how to present data to clients

Shop Smart, Inc., Editor

June 2010-March 2012

Shop Smart empowers consumers to save time and money while shopping

- Increased email subscriber base by 270% by building new merchant relationships and writing targeted content
- Generated more than \$3 million in revenue by writing a blog series on credit card points and sign up bonuses

Marcus Evans, Assistant Manager

August 2007-June 2010

Marcus Evans produces niche business intelligence events for industry experts to benchmark best practices

- Received three promotions in three years despite client budget freezes due to the great recession
- Won team MVP Award in 2007 for sales and leadership contributions

Advantage Freight Network, Supply Chain Operations

July 2006-March 2007

AFN is a third-party logistics provider specializing in expedited full truckload transportation

- Discovered and fostered growth for what would become the 14th largest shipping partner in the network
- Graduated from operations analyst and carrier network development positions to customer sales

EDUCATION

Northwestern University, *Master of Science in Predictive Analytics*

March 2019

Area of focus in advanced modeling, particularly machine learning and deep learning

Indiana University Kelley School of Business, Bachelor of Science in Business

May 2006

• Majored in Business Operations and International Business with minors in French and Italian

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python: Wrote web scrapers to collect data, utilized Pandas for data analysis and reporting automation R: Performed statistical analysis of large data sets, including evaluation of promotion success and client seasonality Keras: Built image recognition, text analytics and time series models for scenario-based forecasts SQL: Mastery of relational databases, designed query templates for fast and accurate reporting Hive: Wrote and standardized queries connecting multiple databases to map customer shopping behavior Project Management: Initiated, planned and executed projects ranging from web scrapers to fraud detection